<Document>
  1. Enforcements are final

  ## Subtext

  - Incidents of admin abuse, negligence, or disputed rulings can be taken up in the
    Discord server. Almost all bans can be appealed in our Discord.
    Contacting the administration team is only acceptable via these means when
    attempting to appeal.

  ## Types of bans
  - Role Ban
    - A.K.A a job ban, this type prevents your character from
      joining/late joining a round as one or more jobs or roles.
      These are usually used in response to problematic
      behavior in specific departments or address gross
      experience in important roles like heads of staff. These
      bans don’t prevent you from switching to the role during a
      round or acting as that role, but doing so is considered ban
      evasion.
  - Game Ban
    - A.K.A a server ban, this ban prevents you from
       connecting to the Jamboree server.

  ## Ban Durations
  - Temporary
    - Temporary bans are lifted automatically after a certain
        period of time. If they are a game ban, they will tell you
        how much time is remaining when you try to connect.
  - Indefinite
    - These bans will only be removed on a successful appeal in
       the discord. Any ban that doesn’t tell you when it expires or
       doesn’t specify otherwise can be assumed to be an
       indefinite ban.
  - Voucher
    - This is an indefinite ban which can be only appealed with
       both a successful appeal and requires a voucher of good
       behavior from the administrative team or a well
       known/decently active SS13/SS14 server. Voucher bans
       can typically only be appealed after at least six months of
       its issuing. A voucher ban is typically placed on players as
       a result of unsuccessful appeal of an indefinite game ban
       by players with a history of bans and of causing issues.
  - Permanent
    - This ban is only appealable if it was inappropriately placed.
       If the appeal results in the ban being determined to be
       appropriately placed, the ban may not be appealed again
       and will not be lifted. These bans will typically be applied to
       players who continually cause problems even after a
       voucher ban or users who have completely unacceptable
       behavior.

  Attempts to circumvent or bypass a game ban will result in a permanent
  ban.
</Document>
