<Document>
  #SUBSECTION 2: Alert Levels and Arresting/Sentencing Procedure

  The following are the different existing alert levels that can occur during a shift as determined by
  the Station AI, Command Department, or other entities alongside the meanings and procedures
  of said alert levels

  [bolditalic]Note: If a threat has been handled or subsided, an alert level should be lowered from what it is
  to Green, with the exception of alert level Red. If on alert level Red, lower to Blue if the threat
  has not been definitively handled. Alert lowering should occur within 15 minutes of a threat
  subsiding or being handled.[/bolditalic]

  [bold][color=green]Green[/color][/bold]
  - All is well.
  - Continue operations as normal!

  Security Operations:
  - All weapons are to be holstered or kept in pockets/suit
  storage unless absolutely required.
  - Long arms must remain inside the brig, exceptions made
  for the HoS and the Warden.
  - Random searches are not permitted without express
  permission by either the HoS or Captain. Searches are still
  permitted if there is reasonable suspicion of a crime.
  - Secure Areas: EVA Storage, Tech Storage, Gravity Generator,
  Engineering Secure Storage, Vault, Armory, Command Zones,
  Security Zones
  - Secure areas are to be left unbolted and ready to use for
  their intended purpose.

  [bold][color=blue]Blue[/color][/bold]
  - There is a known or suspected moderate threat on-board or near the station.
  - Personnel should abide by the following:

  Security Operations:
  - Weapons do not need to be holstered.
  - Long arms are permitted outside of the brig.
  - Random searches are fully permitted. Security personnel
  may detain any personnel refusing a random search.
  - Secure Areas: EVA Storage, Tech Storage, Gravity Generator,
  Engineering Secure Storage, Vault, Armory, Command Zones,
  Security Zones
  - It is recommended all secure areas be bolted unless their
  use is necessary.

  General Crew:
  - Personnel are to report any suspicious activity to their
  nearest Security member or via common radio.
  - Personnel are highly encouraged to exercise caution, even
  if the threat is only suspected.
  - Follow simple safety procedures.

  [bold][color=red]Red[/color][/bold]
  - There are a singular or multiple major threats on-board or near the station.
  - Personnel should abide by the following:

  Security Operations:
  - Random searches are fully permitted and recommended.
  Security personnel may detain any personnel refusing a
  random search in order to conduct said search.
  - Security personnel are expected to fully cooperate with any
  Central Command Staff (ERT, CBURN, Blueshield
  Officers) in order to eliminate the threat to the station
  - In the event of invaders attempting to activate the
  nuclear device on the station, the following are also
  in place.
  - All weapons and chemical restrictions are
  lifted.
  - Dispersal of weapons and armor to all crew
  and building of fortifications is encouraged.
  - Secure Areas: EVA Storage, Tech Storage, Gravity Generator,
  Engineering Secure Storage, Vault, Armory, Command Zones,
  Security Zones
  - Secure Areas may be left bolted or unbolted at the
  discretion of the Command Department

  General Crew:
  - Personnel are to follow the instructions of Security staff, as
  long as they are within the bounds of the Legal Mandate
  and are not acting against the general well-being of the
  station.

  [bold][color=violet]Violet[/color][/bold]
  - There is a confirmed viral outbreak on board the station.
  - Personnel should abide by the following:

  Security Operations:
  - Long arms are permitted outside of the brig.
  - Security personnel should work to contain the threat and
  protect the crew.

  Medical Operations:
  - Medical personnel should begin work on a cure and/or
  vaccine for the infections.
  - Attempts to treat infected patients exhibiting symptoms is
  discouraged.

  General Crew:
  - Personnel are expected to seek safe areas and to acquire
  apparel to resist the infection.
  - Personnel exhibiting symptoms are to be reported to either
  the nearest Security member or over common radio.

  [bold][color=yellow]Yellow[/color][/bold]
  - The station has suffered major atmospheric issues or significant structural
  damage.
  - Personnel should abide by the following:

  Engineering Operations:
  - Engineers are to begin restitution of the issues present to
  the station.
  - Dispersal of emergency internals and, if needed, EVA
  equipment to the crew is recommended.
  - If damage is irreparable or extremely hazardous, it is expected to
  call for the evacuation of the station.

  [bold][color=teal]Gamma[/color][/bold]
  - The station is on its last legs, with almost everyone being dead. Martial Law is in
  effect.
  - Personnel should abide by the following:

  Security Operations:
  - Long arms are permitted and encouraged outside of the
  brig.
  - Arrests, searches, and departmental raids may be
  performed at the discretion of security personnel and do
  not require a warrant.
  - Security is authorized to do whatever actions are deemed
  necessary to neutralise or repel the threat.
  - Security is not bound by Arresting Procedure.
  - Security is not bound by Treatment of Prisoners.

  General Crew:
  - Personnel are to seek any evacuation means possible.

  [bold][color=IndianRed]Delta[/color][/bold]
  - The nuclear destruction mechanism is engaged and the station’s destruction is
  imminent.
  - Personnel should abide by the following:

  Security Operations:
  - Long arms are permitted and encouraged outside of the
  brig.
  - Body armor and helmets are mandatory for Security
  personnel.
  - All weapon and chemical restrictions are lifted.
  - Dispersal of weapons and armor to all crew and building of
  fortifications is encouraged.
  - All crew are encouraged to seek evacuation or assist in
  elimination of the threat.

  [bold][color=lightblue]Octarine[/color][/bold]
  - A cataclysmic noospheric event threatens to envelop realspace.
  - Personnel should abide by the following:

  Security Operations:
  - Long arms are permitted and encouraged outside of the
  brig.
  - Body armor and helmets are mandatory for Security
  personnel.
  - All weapon and chemical restrictions are lifted.
  - Dispersal of weapons and armor to all crew and building of
  fortifications is encouraged.
  - All crew are encouraged to seek evacuation or assist in
  elimination of the threat.

  _________________________________________________

  ## Arresting Procedure

  Arresting procedure is the ideal way to carry out an arrest. Not all can or will be performed this
  way, but they should generally follow this procedure.

  1. Inform the criminal that they are wanted, and why they are wanted. This is void if they
  are visibly armed or in the process of committing a crime.

  2. If compliant, cuff and transport the prisoner to the brig immediately without harming them
  and allow the warden, HoS, or Captain to complete the sentencing. If there is no warden,
  HoS, or Captain, the arresting officer may complete sentencing. If compliant, you do not
  need to stun the criminal/suspect before applying cuffs. If the violation is minor then the
  suspect may be allowed to walk freely to security while accompanied by a security
  member until that liberty is abused.

  3. If resistant, use your nonlethal weaponry until a situation prompts the use of lethal force.
  If successful, transport the prisoner to the brig and allow the warden, HoS, or Captain to
  complete sentencing. If there is no warden, HoS, or Captain, the arresting officer may
  complete sentencing.

  4. If lethal force is used, the suspect must be provided medical aid until they are in a stable
  enough condition to serve their sentence. If lethal force was used in the prevention of a
  capital offense, revival is no longer required.
</Document>
