<Document>
  # SUBSECTION 3: Chain Of Command

  While working aboard this facility, you will be organized into different departments, each led by
  different roles. If you are working under one of these leading roles, you are required to follow
  orders which do not cause any violations. Insubordination is not tolerated and will be treated
  with appropriate measure.

  [bolditalic]Note: The placement of listing does not indicate the hierarchy of power, and rather lists those in
  said departments/their said departments[/bolditalic]

 [color=green][bold]Central Command[/bold][/color]
  - [bold]Cental Command Official[/bold]: Heads over both Central Command and over all other departments.

  [color=DeepSkyBlue][bold]Command[/bold][/color]
  - [bold]Captain[/bold]: Heads over both Command and all other departments besides Central Command
  - [bold]Head Of Security (HoS)[/bold]: Leads Security
  - [bold]Head Of Personnel (HoP)[/bold]: Leads Service
  - [bold]Quartermaster (QM)[/bold]: Leads Logistics
  - [bold]Research Director (RD)[/bold]: Leads Science
  - [bold]Chief Engineer (CE)[/bold]: Leads Engineering
  - [bold]Chief Medial Officer (CMO)[/bold]: Leads Medical

___________________________________________________________________________

  In the event that a captain does not appear during the shift or a captain becomes unrecoverable
  during a shift, a new captain must be selected. This follows a fairly simple step-by-step guide.

  - Step 1: Is there a captain who is alive and present? If so, proceed to step 6. If not,
  proceed to the next step.
  - Step 2: Is there an HOP who is alive and present? If so, proceed to step 6. If not,
  proceed to the next step.
  - Step 3: Is there an HOS who is alive and present? If so, proceed to step 6. If not,
  proceed to the next step.
  - Step 4: All heads may vote on a head to elect as captain, then should proceed to step 6.
  If all heads are not alive and present, proceed to the next step. If all heads are dead or
  unavailable, proceed to the next step.
  - Step 5: If no heads have yet to arrive up until 15 minutes into the shift, crew are
  permitted to take the actions necessary to keep operations on the station stable. If heads
  have arrived during the course of the shift but are now all deceased or incapable of their
  duties, call the emergency shuttle and set the alert level to code red.
  - Step 6: That person is now the Captain
</Document>
