<Document>
  ## Subsection 1: Designation
  For the purposes of operational clarity and liability management, all individuals aboard a
  NanoTrasen installation fall into one of two categories, with the inclusion of one sub-category:

  - [bold]Contracted Personnel[/bold] (The "Crew"): Any individual who has entered into a binding employment contract with NanoTrasen, either through Central Command prior to the beginning of a shift or through the Captain, or the head of the respective department that the individual wishes to work for, during a shift, and currently holds a designated role. As Contracted Personnel, your primary functions are to perform your assigned duties and to adhere to the Code of Conduct.
  - [bold]Non-Contractual Entity[/bold] (The "Non-Crew"): Any biological, synthetic, or extra-dimensional entity not under a current NanoTrasen service contract. This classification includes, but is not limited to: pests (such as mice or moth-roaches), cyborgs, Artificial Intelligences, non-hostile individuals without employment contracts. Non-Contractual Entities which exhibit behaviors which threaten Contracted Personnel or the station as a whole fall under the subcategory of Hostile Entity, as described below.
  - [bold]Hostile Entity[/bold] (The "Enemy"): Any biological, synthetic, or extra-dimensional entity not currently under a NanoTrasen service contract which has exhibited behavior which threatens Contracted Personnel or the station as a whole

  The status of an entity as one of these categories can be changed by the following, with the
  following caveats:

  - [bold]Central Command[/bold]: Central Command has total authority in changing the classification status of all entities.
  - [bold]The Captain[/bold]: The Captain has authority to change the classification status of entities with the exception of those directly under Central Command in the Chain of Command. [bold]Such a change in classification must be announced via the communications console.[/bold]
</Document>
