<Document>
  #SUBSECTION 2: Prisoner Treatment, Searching and Seizure, and Warrants

  Prisoners still have these rights that must be upheld by the Security Department:
  - Prisoners must be granted adequate medical care.
  - Prisoners must be allowed access to basic communications equipment (radios or a
  holopad) so long as it is not abused.
  - Prisoners must be granted clothing, food, water, shelter, and safety. If the brig is no
  longer safe, confinement must be established elsewhere.
  - Prisoners must be given access to legal counsel during an interrogation if requested and
  available.
  - Prisoners must be given their shift mandated PDA after confinement has finished, unless
  there is solid proof of a PDA tampering. In the case of tampering, the tampered PDA is
  to be secured and replaced with a new unit at release.
  - Prisoners must be granted freedom of movement and should not be restrained with
  handcuffs or other implements after incarceration unless there is an undue risk to life
  and limb. Prisoners in permanent confinement should be held in the communal brig and
  only be confined to a solitary cell if they pose a risk to life and limb.

  Revival
  - If lethal force was used to incapacitate a capital offender or an attempted escape
  from permanent confinement, they are no longer eligible to be revived.
  - The CMO, Captain, or HoS may also declare a patient or prisoner to not be
  revived within reason. Example being a patient immediately killing themselves
  after revival, wasting resources.

  A personnel search is a seizure of objects in a person’s backpack, hands, coat, belt, and
  pockets. If any contraband is found during a search, the officer may choose to further the search
  into detainment or simply confiscate the restricted items. After the search is conducted, all legal
  items are to be returned to the person. A crewmate may legally decline any search conducted
  without probable cause or a warrant while on alert level green. This is not applicable on alert
  levels of blue or above.
  - A warrant is a form which specifies “who” is to be searched and “why”. It must be
  stamped by the proper authority according to its creation
  - Security officers can create but cannot approve warrants. The warden or HOS
  must approve officer search warrants.
  - The warden can create a warrant but it must be approved by the HOS or the
  departmental head of the to-be-searched.
  - Warrants written by the Head of Security must be looked over by the Warden,
  Captain, or relevant departmental head.
  - In the event of a skeleton crew where no applicable head is available, the captain
  can serve as a substitute for approval of warrants and departmental searches.
</Document>
