<Document>
  2. Obey the Metashield

  ##Subtext
  - Something that is “shielded” cannot be known by your character during a round
    until the “revealing condition” happens. This also means that your character
    cannot do things based on “shielded” information. Knowing or acting on
    something that is shielded before the revealing condition is met is referred to as
    metagaming.

  - Revealing conditions reveal the shielded information for the round, not for a
    specific instance. This means that once a revealing condition is met in a round,
    the shield no longer applies in any case for the remainder of the round.

  ## Never Revealed IC
  - Some shields are never revealed IC. This means that your
    character can never act about that shielded thing.
  ### The following are shielded:
    - Current game mode and possible antagonists during
      the current game mode.
    - Events from previous rounds.
    - Events you experienced as a different character.
    - All information related to the player of a character
      rather than the character itself. (See “Metafriending
      and Metagrudging” below.”
    - All information gained while dead or a ghost.
    - All information gained while in critical condition or
      unconscious.

  Nuclear Operatives
  - Nuclear Operatives are rumored, and appear in
    popular media, but are not proven. Have fun talking
    about your favorite season of Nukies.

  Changelings
  - Changelings, in the eyes of the public, are an
    exterminated predatory lifeform. They could always
    come back, but not on our station, right?

  Heretics
  - The chaplain is aware of the existence of heretics, but
    the chaplain is always spewing nonsense. What do
    they even mean!?!?

  Cosmic Cult
  - The chaplain is saying words again! Why do they hire
    such weird people?

  Devils
  - The chaplain is now talking about DEVILS? What is
    this nonsense? Devils are just a myth, they can’t be
    real!
  - (Knowledge about the abilities and consequences of
    a Devil deal are not shielded.)

  Zombies
  - Zombies are known galaxy-wide as fictional
    creatures. Nuclear Operatives and Syndicate Agents
    are aware of Romerol and what it can do, but there’s
    no benefit to revealing it to the crew. People likely
    won’t believe you anyway.

  Infections (Once the zombie virus is proven)
  - Such infections have been known to be extinct.
    Luckily though, advanced medicine has been able to
    cure the infection. The cure is not known to the
    public, but it is known to Chemists and Chief Medical
    Officers. The cure is not known to be a cure for the
    zombie virus but is known to be a cure for an infection
    that causes people to become zombies.

  Deathsquad
  - Deathsquad is a sci-fi trope that is well known in the
    galaxy, but not as a real thing. It is a myth, a legend,
    and a story people tell each other. The Deathsquad is
    not real, but some will argue that it is. The only ones
    who know the truth are members of Central
    Command, who desire to keep it secret given its
    purpose.

  Implants
  - Implants are not shielded by default, but the fact they
    are not Nanotrasen (NT) implants is shielded.

  Chameleon Items
  - Chameleon items are shielded. Being suspicious of
    an item being fake or stolen is not shielded, but
    testing items or calling them chameleon is covered by
    this shield.

  Stealth Items
  - The fact that an item can be something other than
    what its visual appearance and examine description
    indicate is shielded. Security may be aware of
    tampered items, but not aware of the specific item
    that is tampered. This means that security may not
    act on the fact that an item is suspicious. (Example:
    Non-NT weapons on a person is suspicious, how did
    they get it on the station?) This shield protects stealth
    items, including protecting them from being tested.

  Metafriending and Metagrudging
  - Giving a person or character preferential treatment based on
    something your character should not know is considered
    metafriending. Treating a person or character negatively
    based on something your character should not know is
    considered metagrudging. Both are not permitted.

  ### Explicitly Not Shielded:
  The following is a list of things that are explicitly not shielded. If
  something is not on this list, it does not mean that it is
  shielded, but if something is on it then it is definitely not
  shielded.

  - The fact that the nuke disk must be protected and
    could be used by a bad actor to destroy the station.
  - Items that are of high value or are desired by the
    Syndicate, and therefore are likely targets of theft.
  - The idea that any Syndicate agent or bad actor has
    goals or objectives that they are attempting to
    accomplish.
  - The number of goals or objectives that a Syndicate
    agent or other bad actor has.
  - The fact that the Syndicate are enemies of
    Nanotrasen, and that they regularly attempt to send
    covert agents to spy on, sabotage, or attack
    Nanotrasen.
  - A character’s typical appearance. Though you should
    keep in mind that multiple characters can share the
    same name.
  - The fact that the Syndicate have covert items capable
    of getting items to them, and that these items are
    known as uplinks.
  - Wizards are not metashielded as the wizards
    federation is well rumored about.
</Document>
